TIFFANY GREVIOUS

(570) 234-4778 | tjgrevious@gmail.com | devchamploo.github.io | codepen.io/DevchamploO

SKILLS & ABILITIES

Languages: Java, JavaScript, PHP, HTML5/CSS3; Frontend: Wordpress, JQuery, React, Redux; Backend: Node.js, Express, Spring Boot, MySQL, MongoDB; Other: GIT, Bash/Shell, D3, unit testing

PROJECTS

Crisis to Hope, https://github.com/DevchamploO/Crisis to Hope

 Web application that scans tweets for possible depression and suicide risk. Built with React, Bootstrap, Node/Express backend server, Twitter API, IBM Watson Tone Analyzer API, and peer reviewed research.

Filler.js, https://github.com/DevchamploO/filler.js

· Light weight JavaScript plugin that autofills filler text inside of HTML. Published to npm.

Fix Your City, https://github.com/DevchamploO/FixYourCity

· Hackathon submission. Report and rank local infrastructural damage to bring awareness and combat urban decay. Built with **React**, **Ruby on Rails**, and the **TomTom API**.

EXPERIENCE

2015 - Current

Computer Repair Technician, Self-employed

- · Communicated with customers to resolve complaints by identifying issues, possible malfunctions or the need for further customer education.
- Diagnosed and repaired hardware/software with desktops, notebooks, netbooks, monitors, and tablets both on and off site.
- · Identified and solved technical issues for Windows and Macs.
- \cdot Built custom computers from the ground up.

2012 - 2015

Analyst, Appen Global

- · Partnered with web development teams to enhance functionality, user experience, online brand positioning and advertising.
- · Conducted research, evaluations, and provided feedback of various data sets.
- · Improved the quality of artificial intelligence for large Social Media companies and Google.

EDUCATION

2018

Software Engineering, 42 Sillicon Valley

2008 - 2012

Media Arts, New Jersey City University